

PHD CANDIDATE · NEUROSCIENCE AND NEUROTECHNOLOGY

Aydınlar Mah. Cahit Sıtkı Sok. No: 11/5 Dikmen Ankara/Turkey

□ (+90)530 111 530 1 | ■ meltem.atay@metu.edu.tr | □ gmeltematay | □ meltemiatay |

♣ https://meltemiatay.github.io/

As a graduate student in Neuroscience and Neurotechnology field, I am passionate about discerning the interplay between human cognition and artificial intelligence. Machine learning, deep learning and their applications into brain imaging data are main research fields that excite me in addition to my overarching interest in understanding brain connectome changes during aging process. Accordingly, I am very much interested in applications of recurrent neural networks in the field of neuroscience and what they could offer for deep learning research area along with generative adversarial networks. Merging of computational neuroscience with deep learning has revolutionary potential in addressing a wide range of outstanding problems throughout the computational sciences. Hence, I would like to be part of this astonishing revolution in the field of artificial intelligence as a deep learning researcher.

Education ____

Middle East Technical University, Institute of Natural and Applied Sciences

Ankara, Turkey

Ph.D. IN NEUROSCIENCE AND NEUROTECHNOLOGY

September 2015 - Present

• Ph.D Dissertation Title: Machine Learning on Neuroimages for Diagnosis of Neurodegenerative Diseases.

Middle East Technical University, Department of Mathematics

Ankara, Turkey

SCIENTIFIC PREPARATION PERIOD BEFORE PH.D. PROGRAM

September 2014 - September 2015

Hacettepe University, Institute of Health Sciences

Ankara, Turkey

M.Sc. IN MEDICAL BIOCHEMISTRY

September 2012 - August 2014

• M.Sc. Dissertation Title: Effects of Statins on Human Serum Butyrylcholinesterase and Erythrocyte Acetylcholinesterase.

Online Education

Udacity Deep Learning Nanodegree

Online

FACEBOOK PyTorch Challenge Winner

Graduated. February 2019

• I was one of the fully funded by Facebook in a group of 300 scholars selected from 6000 active participants through a capstone project challenge of flower species classification .

Honors & Awards __

Graduate Courses Performance Award, Middle East Technical University, 3.53/4.00 cGPA

2016

Institute of Natural and Applied Sciences

High Honor, Hacettepe University Department of Medical Biochemistry

2014

Technical Skills

3.44/4.00 cGPA.

Programming Languages

Most experience: Python and

MATLAB

Little experience: Java, HTML, CSS, SQL

and PHP

Software Frameworks

Deep Learning: Tensorflow-Keras,

PvTorch

Neuroscience: SPM12

Academic Publications

NeurIPS 2018 Online Gallery Submission

MACHINE LEARNING FOR CREATIVITY AND DESIGN WORKSHOP

December 2018

- Atay M., EbruGAN: Digital Art Creation Based On Mixture of Traditional Turkish Art and Human Faces.
- http://www.aiartonline.com/community/meltem-atay-sebnem-ozdemir-aysin-tasdelen/

2018 Innovations in Intelligent Systems and Applications (INISTA)

IEEE Xplore Proceedings.

MACHINE LEARNING: METHODOLOGIES, APPLICATIONS AND TRENDS (MLMAT 2018)

July 2018

- Bircanoğlu C., Atay M., Beşer F., Genç O., Kızrak M-A., RecycleNet: Intelligent Waste Sorting Using Deep Neural Networks.
- · Transfer learning experimentation with little number of natural images

MATTER METU

Undergraduate Research Journal

December 2016

Atay M., Baskın Ö., Cantürk E., Kara İ., Koçak İ., Kürkcü A., Şahin B., Alternative Rehabilitation Solutions for Cerebral Palsy.

Posters and Presentations

Queer in AI NeurIPS 2019 Workshop

Vancouver, Canada

ORAL PRESENTATION

December 2019

· Atay MG., Transformer-Based Unsupervised Machine Translation Study from Gender-less Languages

The Association of European Operational Research Societies Conference (EURO-k 2019) - InteriOR 2019

Dublin, Ireland - Medan, Indonesia

ORAL PRESENTATION · Atay MG., Weber G-W., Classification and Generation of Digital Marble Art (EBRU) by revisiting OR via Deep Learning

Machine Learning Summer School in Steppe

Ankara, Turkey

June - December 2019

POSTER PRESENTATION

August 2017

Atay M., Hacettepe, August 2017. Motif and Pattern Design Generation using Deep Convolutional Generative Adversarial Networks

New techniques in Machine Learning and Data Mining Summer School

Ankara, Turkey

POSTER PRESENTATION

ORAL PRESENTATION

September 2016

• Atay M., Halıcı U., Intelligent Methods for Early Diagnosis of Parkinson's disease.

The Association of European Operational Research Societies Conference (EURO-K 2016)

Poznan, Poland

June - August 2019

• Atay M., Weber G-W., Making Art by Inspirations of Mathematics.

Teaching Experience _

Lead Instructor Ankara

DEEP LEARNING TÜRKIYE, ANKARA STUDY GROUP

February 2018 - July 2018

- Lead a study group to complete convolutional neural networks lecture series of Coursera deeplearning ai course.
- · Translated and prepared educational material for the group of people with different educational backgrounds

Lecturer - Voluntary Teacher

Ankara

ANKARA YILDIRIM BEYAZIT UNIVERSITY

January 2018 - June 2018

- Gave introductory lecture series to computer engineering undergraduate students,
- Prepared a basic curriculum for Python programming and fundamentals of deep learning.

Voluntary Teaching Assistant

Ankara

COMPUTATIONAL NEUROSCIENCE COURSE - NSNT 501

September 2017 - January 2018

- Helped to prepare tutorials about MATLAB and Python programming.
- · Introduced the basics of computational neuroscience to ten graduate students from different research disciplines.

Instructor METU - Ankara

DEEPMETU, 16 WEEK LONG COURSE

September 2017 - January 2018

- Collaborated with engineering students to form DeepMETU a student lead applied course.
- Took part in the curriculum, gave a lecture about auto encoders, generative adversarial networks and image style transfer algorithm.

Participant METU-Ankara

INTERDISCIPLINARY DESIGN STUDIO AT METU, DEPARTMENT OF ARCHITECTURE AND DESIGN

January - April 2016

- Summarized results in undergraduate level journal (MATTER).
- Participated in several industrial seminars.
- Actively took part in finalizing design process of a rehabilitation solution for children in need, especially for rehabilitation of upper extremity problems in cerebral palsy.
- Guided a group of undergraduate students from different backgrounds into design process.
- Learned simple architecture of embedded systems and applied basic codes on Arduino-Uno platform.

Voluntary Lecture Assistant

Ankara

TUTORIAL SESSIONS OF APPLIED BIOCHEMISTRY LABORATORY, HACETTEPE UNIVERSITY, FACULTY OF MEDICINE

September 2012 - August 2014

Vanaguus Dritigh Calumbia

- As a MSc. student, I gained experience at protein purification techniques, spectroscopy technology and basic scientific quantification.
- Participated and assisted in laboratory tutorial sessions in Biochemistry laboratories.
- · Gave tutorials to group of graduate and undergraduate students about spectroscopy techniques.
- Guided summer internship of several undergraduate students

Conferences and Courses _____

December 2019	Speaker , Queer in Al NeurlPS 2019 Workshop	vancouver, British Columbia,
		Canada
December 2019	Reviewer , Woman in Machine Learning Workshop 2019	Vancouver, British Columbia,
	co-located with NeurIPS 2019	Canada
July-August 2019	Attendee, Neurohackademy 2019 Summer Course	Seattle, Washington, USA
June 2019	Attendee , International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2019)	Long Beach, California, USA
December 2018	Attendee, Social Conference on Machine Learning (SOCML 2018)	Toronto, Ontario, Canada
January-April 2016	Attendee, Interdisciplinary Design Studio (IDS 2016)	Ankara, Turkey

References _____

1	Uğur Halıcı, Ph.D, Ph.D Thesis Supervisor,	halici@metu.edu.tr
	METU Neuroscience and Neurotechnology Department Head	
2	Bülent Elibol, MD-Ph.D, Ph.D Thesis Co-Supervisor	elibol@hacettepe.edu.tr
3	Gerhard-Wilhelm Weber, Ph.D, Professor,	gerhard.weber@put.poznan.pl
	Affiliated Faculty of Neuroscience and Neurotechnology Department	